

Email jschacosta@gmail.com

Address

Paulstraße 34, Berlin. 10557, Germ any

Phone

+56971014264

Date of birth Feb 19, 1994

Nationality Chilean

Link

www.linkedin.com/in/johannsch

_

Skills

Creative Strategy

Cross-Team Collaboration

Team Management

Javascript

SQL

Mongo DB

Scrum

Vue js

Visual Basic

Matlab

Ansys

AWS

Git

Node is

DMAIC

П

Languages

Spanish Native

Intermediate. Toefl Certificate

Johann Schwarze Full stack - Project Manager

I'm Software developer with 2+ years of experience in the industry.

Mechanical engineer by profession, currently workin as **Full Stack Project Manager** developing an app for the creative industry.

Interested in the development of renewable / non-conventional energies and latest technologies of software.

Passionate about sports and teamwork to achieve the proposed goals.

Experience

Full stack - Project Manager

 $\textbf{Comercial Unabase Limitada} \quad \tilde{\textit{N}u}\tilde{\textit{noa}}, \textit{Regi\'on Metropolitana}, \textit{Chile} \\ \textbf{May 2021 - Present}$

Team leader of the development application both in technical and communicational aspects.

- Lead the development and design team meeting customer expectations
- I critically analyze the information coming back from the project team to verify accuracy in both solution quality and estimated time, without having to rely solely on your technical and design teams.
- Development of new functionalities in the back-end to relate the previous version of the application with the new version in process.
- Hire and train new members of the project. developers (Back-End, Front-End) as designers (UI-UX)

Full stack Developer

Comercial Unabase Limitada *Ñuñoa, Región Metropolitana, Chile* Feb 2021 - May 2021

Full-Stack Developer responsible for developing and designing the new version of the company's application (WPA).

- Perform front-end and back-end development tasks using the MEVN stack (Mongo Db, express, vue js, node js).
- Lead the development team in response to customer requests.
- Be encharge of task planning using scrum tools.

Frontend Developer

Comercial Unabase Limitada *Ñuñoa, Región Metropolitana, Chile* Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Responsible for developing the design and development of the new user interfaces for the new version of the application. (PWA).

- Comply with assigned tasks according to customer requirements and deliver solutions for new developments.
- generate flowcharts of user interfaces prior to each development

Mechanical Engineer

MAF CHILE SPA *Peñaflor, Región Metropolitana, Chile* May 2019 - Nov 2019

Company dedicated to the export of fruits.

The main role was to evaluate the efficiency and functionality of all the machines in the company.

- I had working in a group of 4 engineers and technicians.
- Achieve important reduction costs, finding more efficient machines for the fruit exportation process.
- We did a research to discover the possible variables that affects the performance of the production findings more suitable equipment for the production line.

Engineering Trainee

Good Year S.A.I.C Maipú, Región Metropolitana, Chile Jan 2019 - May 2019

Work related to the Quality Department, Product Development area. Gathering and analyzing information about the quality of the tire, tire failures and Optimization of the production lines.

 Use of continuous improvement tools such as DMAIC cycle and Lean Manufacturing, creation of quality analysis systems for tires using different softwares.

Maintenance Engineer

Empresas Ariztía Santiago, Chile Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

Work related to the maintenance department, scheduling maintenance for the machines in the production line.

- Develop a virtual library of spare parts, from different suppliers.
- I learned about the production line and process in a big company.

Education

Mechanical Enginnering

Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María Santiago, Chile Mar 2012 - Nov 2019

Mechanical civil engineer with mention in energy.

My specialization in thermodynamic processes and fluid mechanics.